Finding Aid for Health System (University of Michigan) publications, 1892-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Marketing/Outreach
  The Marketing/Outreach series (1 linear foot, 1982-2006) consists of various brochures and newsletters promoting the University Hospital including Community Beat (currently published) and Medical Center Report (replaced by Advance)
  - Annual report (Office of Planning and Marketing) 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Brochures, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Calendar of events (Box 8)
  - Guidelines for the Use and Application of the Medical Center Signature (Box 8)
  - Newsletters/Journals
    - Advance (replaced Medical Center report), 1982-1996, 13 folders (Box 8)
    - Community Beat, 2000-2006 (Box 8)
    - Healthwise, 1987-1998, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Marketing Update, 1984-1991 (Box 8)
    - Medical Center Report (replaced by Advance), 1974/1975-1981, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - University Hospital / University Hospitals, 1978-1986, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Office of Health Science Relations (Box 8)
  - Public opinion surveys 1986-1988 (Box 8)
- Nursing Services 1983-1999
  The Nursing Services series consists of publications on the Associate Director of Nursing, Educational Services for Nursing, and the nursing staff, (0.75 linear feet, 1983-1999) including annual reports and newsletters, 1985-1999
  - Associate Hospital Director for Nursing
    - New Direction/New Directions (newsletter), 1988 (Box 9)
  - Department of Psychiatric Nursing
    - Psychiatric Nursing Newsletter, 1986, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Educational Services for Nursing
    - Educational Opportunities for Nursing (Educational Opportunities for You in Nursing, 1989-1991/92 (Box 9)
    - Educational Services for Nursing Manual, circa 1981 (Box 9)
    - Flyers 1991 (Box 9)
    - Newsletters
      - Newsletter, 1985, 1989 (Box 9)
      - Nursing Education Newsletter, 1990-1999, 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Professional Achievement of Nurses, 1982/1983-1990/1991 (Box 9)
  - Nursing Services
    - Annual Report (Perspectives in Nursing), 1994, 1998-1999 (Box 9)
    - Clinical Nursing Practice Manual, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Corporate Nursing Services Programs, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Directories 1986, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Management Modules for Nursing Services: Module 3: the Employment Interview, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Newsletters
      - Focus: Clinical Inquiry, 1990 (Box 9)
      - Focus on Nursing at University of Michigan Hospitals, 1983 (Box 9)
      - Horizons, 1986-1997 (Box 9)
    - Recruitment 1986, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
- Services 1963-1998
  The Services series (1.75 linear feet, 1963-1998) includes various publications of service units within the Hospital including: Biomedical Research, Educational Services, Heart Care Program, Infection Control, Information Systems, Materiel Services, Nutrition Services, Patient Services, Pharmacy, Survival Flight, and Volunteer Services.
  - Brochures (Box 9)
  - Biomedical Research
    - Catalog of Services, 1992-1995 (Box 9)
    - Computing Projects Directory, undated (Box 9)
  - Educational Services
    - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Commemorative Health Care Symposia 1985-1990 (Box 9)
    - Furstenberg Student Study Center (Box 9)
    - Instructional resources (catalog), Media Library 1982 (Box 9)
    - Patient Management Simulations: a Resource Catalog, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Software for Health Sciences Education, fourth edition, 1993 (Box 9)
    - UMFRA: Continuation for Research, Report no. 7, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Heart Care Program (Box 9)
  - Infection Control
    - Infection Control (newsletter), 1984 (Box 10)
  - Information Systems and Services
    - Information Services Division
      - Annual Report, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Office of the Health Sciences Information Technology and Networking
      - Megabyte (newsletter), 1993 (Box 10)
    - The University of Michigan Hospitals Information Systems Strategic Plan, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Materiel Services Department
    - Materiel Management News 1983-1984 (Box 10)
    - Materiel Matters (newsletter), 1984-1991 (Box 10)
  - Nutrition Services (includes: Clinical Nutrition Services, Department of Dietetics, Parenteral and Enthral Nutrition Team)
    - Diet Manual of the University Hospital
      - 1935 (Box 10)
      - 1944 (Box 10)
      - 1955 (Box 10)
    - Meal Planning for Weight Control 1984 (Box 10)
    - Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition Manual 1982-1984 (Box 10)
    - Physicians Handbook of Nutrition Support first and second editions, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
    - Physician's Handbook of Nutrition Support: Maternal & Pediatric, 2nd edition, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Training Course in Dietetics [1950s ?] (Box 10)
  - Patient Services
    - Patient handbooks 1963-1994, undated (Box 10)
    - Patient Visitor Accommodation Location Study, 1985 (Box 10)
    - Wilmot House Newsletter, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Pharmacy (Department of Pharmacy Services)
    - Michigan Drug Letter (newsletter), 1989-1996, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Pharmacy Newsletter for Physicians, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Survival Flight
    - The Blade (newsletter), 1989 (Box 10)
    - Posters (Folder 1)
  - Volunteer Services
    - Annual report 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Brochures and manuals, miscellaneous and undated (Box 10)
    - University of Michigan Medical Center Volunteers: Caring for Generations (newsletter), 1991-1998 (Box 10)
- Women's Health 1999-2006
  (includes Women's Hospital and Women's Health Resource Center)
  Publications in the Women's Health (Women's Hospital) series (0.25 linear feet, 1999-2006) include newsletters and brochures on women's services at the Hospital.
  - Brochures (Box 10)
  - Newsletters
    - Women's Health, 1999-2006 (Box 10)
    - Women's Health Resource Center News, 2002 (Box 10)